I move my bangs which I cut short
切り過ぎた前髪揺らす
A wind of the shining spring blows
キラリ春の風が吹く
in the albums I hold deep within my heart
胸の奥のアルバムに
The smiles of my treasured friends are countless
大切な仲間の笑顔がいっぱい
As if we were steadily growing taller
ぐんぐん背が伸びるように
we have come together to lift one another up
お互い高め合ったよね
while locking eyes
目と目合わせながら
With this pure heart
まっ白なこの心で
The sound of the dream we performed
奏でた夢の音
In those days when we made the truest of hopes to bloom
本気の希望を咲かせた日々
But nobody was ever alone
だってひとりじゃ何も出来なかった
because I saw them all facing intently forward
ちゃんと前向くみんなを見てたから
and so we have arrived here
ここに辿り着いた
There has been born into this world
この世界に生まれて
no person whom we can do without
居なくていい人はいない
With each twig, leaf, and flower connected
枝も葉も花も繋がりあって
we grow them all into a great tree
大きい木へと育ってく
We wrote on looseleaf
ルーズリーフに書いた
an unfinished tale
未完成のものがたり
Each person keeps on drawing it
ひとりひとりが続き描いて
and from this we have already begun our map to the future
そこからまた始まる、未来地図
As if you were leaping over a vault
跳び箱を越えるみたいに
you overcame your unease
不安乗り越えたかった
But only 5mm more to go
だけど5ミリでも上を
striving for it is tough and rather disheartening
目指すのがキツくてかなり凹んだ
That you did it without showing your tears
ナミダ見せずにいたのは
is testimony to the belief you have in yourself
自分信じてた証
Your pains become as feathers
痛みは羽根になる
For the grammar I learned
覚えた文法より
Friendships which gave me strength
力になる友情
Even the roots of my troubles are the pieces of tomorrow
悩みの種さえ明日(あす)のカケラ
All along we’ve been challenging one another through our rivalries
ずっと切磋琢磨した私たち
From that day having grown more steadfast
もっとあの日より逞しくなって
we hand over our light
ヒカリを手渡すよ
All over this world
この世界のどこかで
everyone is trying their best
みんなが頑張ってる
Simply by imagining so we can make ourselves happy
そう想うだけで元気になれる
beneath the same vast sky
同じ広い空の下
The times we came together for support
支え合った時間が
are as a map for the days when we have gone astray
迷った日の地図になる
A cherry blossom which heads for the future at the front line
未来へ向かうさくら前線
We make these footprints to shine, an unknown guidepost
足跡輝かせる、未知標 〜ミチシルベ〜
What meaning there is in this world
この世界にいる意味
we do not yet know
まだ　わからないけど
But if we dig out some sort of tunnel, surely
どんなトンネルも抜ければきっと
there will be a dazzling view
まぶしい景色があるよね
We wrote on looseleaf
ルーズリーフに書いた
an unfinished tale
未完成のものがたり
Each person keeps on drawing it
ひとりひとりが続き描いて
and from this we have already begun our map to the future
そこからまた始まる、未来地図